Hey, Rin. Wake up.
Come over here.
It's only a dream. Don't be scared.
Huh?
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことは　分かんない
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau nanika ga chigau
これって　犠牲とは違う　何かが違う
This is different from sacrificing, very different.
batsugeemu jaa nante omou wa nai
罰ゲームじゃあ　なんて思うわない
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
tte nande nanoka ha wakannai
って　なんでなのかは　分かんない
I can't really say well what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと　釈然としないけど
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nantemonjanai
キミの存在　今大事だ　なんてもんじゃない
but "important" cannot be used to describe your existence any more.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai
終わらないことなんて　この世のどこにもない
There's nothing that will last forever without coming to an end.
naku no ha tsurai janai no
泣くのは辛いじゃないの
Crying is a very painful thing
I know! Sweet drops! Sweet drops!
zutto yume mite itaine
ずっと　夢見ていたいね
I have always wanted to dream
motto yasashiku shitaine
もっと　優しくしたいね
To be able to be more gentle
kimi to iraretara happy!
キミと居られたら　happy!
Just being together with you is happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って　強いね
Girls are strong,
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど　時々　弱いね
but at times, they are weak.
bokura no negai ha happy! happy! happy...
僕らの願いは　happy! happy! happy...
Our wish is to be happy! Happy! Happy!
sonna hibi mo happy!
そんな日々も happy!
Such happy days!
Just wanna make you happy...
Here, I'm counting on you.
You helped me like that when we were at Grandpa's place, right?
Is that so?
You know, I want my own kitchen knife.
That's a bit too early.
There are some made just for kids.
Are you serious?
Let me think about it.
All right, hurry up and finish eating.
We have to get going soon.
Isn't the baby cute?
Yeah.
I'm Kawachi Daikichi, the relative of Kaga Rin's father.
I'm currently living together with Rin-san... I mean Rin.
Um, you are Yoshii Masako-san, Rin's mother; am I right?
Er, what?
Uh, me? Oh, yeah.
I want to meet you directly and have a talk.
I will go somewhere near where you live; please tell me the place to meet.
Meeting place?
W-Where...
Near the shopping district—
Sorry, but I don't even know where you live.
Kaga Rin
Wow, it's so cute.
So many of them, you're a pretty good Mom.
This flower too?
That's right. It's called an embroidery.
I see, it's amazing.
When you're a little older, I'll teach you how to do it.
Really?
Your hands are very delicate.
So how do you intend to handle it?
I'll meet her first and then decide.
I'll leave Rin to you.
Daikichi.
Yeah?
This is very important, so make sure you have a proper talk.
Your mom can have fun with Rin-chan, in the meantime.
This place is actually quite close to Grandpa's place.
Welcome!
Table for one?
There will be another person coming later.
No smoking zone.
Drink slowly, don't choke.
It's so stressful.
Yeah, I understand how it feels.
American coffee, please.
Sure! A cup of American coffee.
Will that be all?
Yes.
That's really great, Saionji-sensei.
As expected of you.
Now you just have to put the characters through some traumatic events.
I-Isn't that too many?
No, it'll be perfect this way.
That's strange.
I couldn't find a single clue about her at Grandpa's place at all.
To think that she even lives somewhere so near?
Well then, Sensei, I'm counting on you.
Thanks for the hard work.
Such a way of escaping after abandoning a child is just too careless.
Mommy, I want to pee!
OK, hold it for a while.
Sign: Yoshii Masako
Hello, where are you right now?
Oh, I'm already inside the shop.
What?
S-Souichi-san?
Wrong. I'm his grandson.
She totally looks like a kid.
U-Um, I'm really sorry. You look really alike.
No, it's fine. I get that a lot from others lately.
But Souichi-san seems to looked much kinder, or how should I put it?
I brought a photo of Rin with me.
Oh, thanks.
This was taken this year, at a rice-cake-pounding event at the daycare.
She really looks like a big sister.
Someone seemed to have addressed you as sensei earlier on.
Y-You saw it?
But the name is...
It's for my work.
Sorry, I was rushing through the scripts last night,
so I'm a little disorganized now.
Was it because of work that you decided to abandon Rin?
Er...
It looks like you made Rin think you were an assistant.
Has it been that way since she was a baby?
It is, indeed, because of work.
But it's also true that I was Souichi-san's assistant.
I couldn't treat Rin as my own daughter.
I had decided that back when I was pregnant.
E-Excuse me, I don't understand the meaning of that.
My manga are not always well received.
It wasn't easy getting a major job, but then I found out I was pregnant.
Besides, this isn't a job that can be done while looking after a child.
But Souichi-san still convinced me to give birth.
At the time, I was either working or sleeping.
I got a little bigger every day.
And then, it's strange, I even thought Rin looked adorable and cute when she was born.
It was strange?
Even though I kept saying I was not her mother, I tried really hard to work and take care of her.
But getting up early is still too painful.
Sometimes, I even have to meet the editor in the middle of the night.
It's physically impossible for me not to sleep in the morning.
I heard that Rin spent some nights at your apartment.
Yes.
Did you go out at night even then?
It's more of midnight rather than at night.
I only went out for a bit after Rin fell asleep.
Sometimes I'd have Souichi-san look after her.
Rin still wakes up at night, even now.
When she wakes up, how will she feel if there isn't anyone there?
Have you ever thought about that?
But... then how do you expect me to raise a child by myself?
That's why Grandpa suggested the three of you live together.
I'll keep living with Rin; is that fine with you?
Yes.
I'm no longer Rin's mother.
So I have no right to decide how she lives.
You're still the one who gave birth to her.
T-That has nothing to do with this.
How exactly do you feel about Rin?
Is she important to you or not?
I... I don't know.
Hey, I have a request.
What is it?
Please allow her to adopt your surname when she starts school.
What? Surname?
It will leave a bad memory if her surname is different from her guardian.
Can you promise me just this one thing?
Well, I understand what you mean.
But I can't promise you.
She's always been called Kaga Rin.
How can she change her own name so easily?
I'm a woman.
There's no need to feel a sense of longing, or be stubborn about my surname.
It'll have to change eventually.
Rin is a woman too. I'm sure she'll feel the same way.
No, Rin is only 6 years old.
But that's not the point.
This is only a one-sided opinion on your part—
There's only one thing that's important.
That's the name Souichi-san gave her, which is "Rin".
That is all there is. Excuse me.
Hey, I'm a guy.
I don't quite understand those things that you said.
But, I'll discuss this over with Rin.
Discuss?
Don't you think it's cruel to let such a young child decide—
I...
I will do what I feel is best for Rin.
Besides, deciding for her is even more cruel.
I will hear how she feels about it, and then we will both decide this together.
I will then inform you of the outcome.
She's definitely an imbecile, I'm sure of it.
In any case, how could she just abandon such a small and adorable child?
That makes no sense!
But she's still concerned about Rin.
It's just that she's a pretty eccentric person or something.
She doesn't seem to notice how much trouble she's causing others.
What are you saying?!
Of course it's natural for a mother to worry about her daughter!
But if she really worries about her, she'll surely want to meet her!
Now, now, maybe she has some sort of difficulty.
Here you go.
Your Grandpa, seriously what did he see in her?
Well, it doesn't matter now.
But it's just that she asked me to allow Rin to use my surname when she starts elementary school.
Oh, I approve of this as well.
What?
It's obviously better for a child to have the same surname as the guardian.
About that, I understand; but how do I explain it to Rin?
I mean, she has her own surname.
Oh, she's a girl after all.
She will have to change her surname after getting married.
This again!
What are you making a fuss about?
Compared to letting others gossip about her surname which will hurt her,
isn't it better for her to use our surname at school?
What? Is this something that can be changed easily?
There'll be lots of problems once she attends elementary school.
It's inevitable.
Well then, I will adopt Rin.
What?
If she agrees to it, then she will really be Kawachi Rin.
Yes, it's more natural this way.
What do you mean?! Don't say something that important so carelessly.
I'm not careless!
Anyway, it's something that has to be decided sooner or later.
So it doesn't matter when!
Now, now, now...
It's not the same!
It is!
Absolutely!
In any case, I don't intend to hand her to anyone.
Also, these things should never have happened to her.
I'm willing to go all-out for her sake.
Sign: Kids' Knife
Here you go.
Is this for me?
Yes, it's for you.
But you can only use it when I'm with you.
I will let you use it if you can promise me that.
Yes.
I'll make some curry for you.
Are you serious?
Today!
Let's make it tomorrow.
Oh? Do I slice or cut?
Oh. Let me try.
Just like that.
Daikichi can really slice well.
Well, it's to be expected, since I've been living alone for so long.
Come, you have a go too.
Do it slowly.
Don't drink the bath water.
Come, put your shoulders under and count to ten.
One, two, saury mushrooms, burdock's six crocodile, seven, nine!
One, two, three, four, five, six...
Daikichi, you're slow!
Don't rush yourself to eat.
OK.
Hey, Rin.
What is it?
It's nothing.
Rin's curry is delicious.
Do I have to do that?
Ah, no. It's all right.
Hey, I'm not your father.
Yeah.
I'm also not your brother.
No one will think like that.
I'm just stating an example.
I'm only asking what am I to you?
Daikichi.
That's my name.
Listen carefully, this has to be what you want.
Which means to say... how do I put it?
I'll be your...
Your real father, how's that?
Daikichi as my father?
So, in that way, your name will be changed to Kawachi Rin.
Kawachi... Rin.
No.
Why not?
Isn't it better to have a father?
My father is Grandpa.
I am OK with my name as Kaga Rin.
It's important to have the same surname as Grandpa.
I see.
Daikichi can remain as Daikichi, it's fine.
Daikichi?
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
This is sweat!
It's only March.
Shut up! Hurry and open your mouth!
I already opened wide; it's because you were crying.
I told you I wasn't crying!
Wider a bit.
Yes.
From now on, this place shall be your home forever.
OK.
Sign: Congratulations for graduating
You cannot forget trust.
Congratulations for graduating
Because daybreak will eventually come.
Our dreams; we must never lose sight of them.
They will eventually come true one day.
The very first step, that first step towards tomorrow.
From today onwards, it will be an entirely new beginning.
Tangerine Group
Draw your courage and take that very big first step.
I understand.
You'll get fat like this.
Does it matter?
I'm an imbecile, after all.
Can I have one?
No way.
nichiyou no hare ta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumono michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通いなれたいつもの道が　まぶしく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らすあたたかい太陽と　となりに君がいれば
The warm sun is shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
While we're feeling so merry
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe ha doko made mo
声はどこまでも
Our voices are everywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
maiagaru kaze ni nori
まいあがる風にのり
Riding on the soaring wind
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe mo tobi haneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
Only a baby needs someone to hug them.
Sayaka-chan said before.
What?
How's that possible?
Even for adults, there are times when we want to be hugged by someone.
But you're a grown-up, so why?
Well, I don't know.
Is it still OK if I'm a first grader?
Sure, why not?
I can hug you anytime you want, you know.
What?
Sorry, I should have given you a hug that time.
When Daikichi cries again next time, I will give him a hug.
Just exactly...
Don't you worry!
...am I the one looking after Rin, or is she looking after me?
I'm starting to be unsure of it.